Suman Kumar

Experienced Full Stack Developer who likes to work with development teams and product owners to ideate software solutions. Skilled in developing both client-side and server-side, managing well-functioning databases and applications.

To play an integral part in the creation of the future that the organization is committed to fulfilling, and in the process, developing myself, standing up to challenges and causing a breakthrough in my performance.

EDUCATION

Himachal Pradesh University, Shimla — *Master of Computer Applications*

2014 - 2017

WRS GC Dehri Kangra, Himachal Pradesh – *Bachelor of Science(Mathematics)*

2011 - 2014

EXPERIENCE

Antier Solutions, Mohali – Full Stack *Developer*Jan 2019- March 2020

Griffons Teach(Innsite, Australia) – *MERN Full Stack Developer (Remote)*

March 2020- March 2022

AI Machines Inc, US – React UI Developer (Remote)

March 2022- Present



+91-8679867067 suman.kalia235@gmail.com

SKILLS

Frontend - ReactJs with a vast experience in working advance state management tools like Redux, Context Api,
Middleware such as Thunk and Sagas.

Backend - NodeJs(ExpressJs)

Database - MongoDB

Knowledge of Git

LANGUAGES

Hindi, English

LINKEDIN PROFILE https://www.linkedin.com/in/suman-kumar-078b4 140

PROJECTS

Moon Assist Gush Coin and Crypto Exchange

Worked as a React Developer..

180 Markets

Worked as a React Developer.

Link - https://180markets.com.au/

Cloud Collect SAAS Platform

Worked as a MERN Stack Developer.

Link - https://cloudcollect.io/

Dorpee

Worked as a React Developer.

Link - https://dorpee.com/

TPZ

Worked as a MERN Stack Developer.

Ginger Sport and Quest Football Academy

Working as a MERN Stack Developer from November 2020.

Link - https://gingersport.com.au/

AutoEngage AI

Working as a React Developer.